<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--Code for string selection in the FishDetails relies on specific naming format of "_overview", "_appearance" etc.-->
    <!--Input data for northern pike.-->
    <string name="northern_pike_overview">One of the most valuable commercial freshwater species in the northwest, the Northern Pike is a strong, persistent fighter attracting many fishermen because of the challenge it presents. </string>
    <string name="northern_pike_appearance"><b>-</b>Large, elongated body.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Dark green to brown body with light, yellowish or white spots.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Dark back fades to creamy white belly.10
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Fully scaled cheek and partially scaled gill cover.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>10 pores on underside of lower jaw.</string>
    <string name="northern_pike_size"><b>-</b>Length: 45-75 centimetres (18-30 inches)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.9-4.3 kilograms (2-9.5 pounds)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario Record: 19.1 kilograms (42.1 pounds)</string>
    <string name="northern_pike_habitat">As a cool-water species, the Northern Pike\'s habitat consists of slow, heavily vegetated rivers or the weedy bays of lakes. During the height of the summer, the Northern Pike
                                        can be found in deep water to avoid high temperatures.
                                        \n\nThe Northern Pike\'s breeding grounds include areas that flood only in the spring and early summer that may be dry the remainder of the year. Northern Pike swim through vegetated areas
                                        of shallow water, randomly scattering eggs which then attach to the vegetation.</string>

    <!--Input data for Largemouth Bass.-->
    <string name="largemouth_bass_overview">The most popular gamefish in North America, the Largemouth Bass are sought after for there vigorous resistance.</string>
    <string name="largemouth_bass_appearance"><b>-</b>Back and sides are green to olive.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Broken Horizontal stripe along body.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Large, wide lower jaw slightly longer than upper jaw.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Two joined dorsal fins, separation more obvious than Smallmouth Bass.</string>
    <string name="largemouth_bass_size"><b>-</b>Length: 25-55 centimetres (10-22 inches)
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Weight 0.7-1.8 koligrams (1.5-4 pounds)
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 4.7 kilograms (10.4 pounds)</string>
    <string name="largemouth_bass_habitat">The Largemouth Bass can be found in the upper levels of warm water of small, shallow lakes or bays. It is almost always found close to soft bottoms, stumps
                                           and in a variety of sub-emergent and emergent vegetation, especially waterlilies, cattails and pondweeds.
                                           \n\nThe Largemouth Bass prefers spawning areas with a firm bottom of sand, mud or gravel.</string>

    <!--Input data for Yellow Perch-->
    <string name="yellow_perch_overview">The Yellow Perch is a freshwater fish with an almost circumpolar distribution in the northern hemisphere and is both a important recreational and commercial fish species.</string>
    <string name="yellow_perch_appearance"><b>-</b>An elongate, oval body.
                                           \n\n<b>-</b>Two well-seperated dorsal fins.
                                           \n\n<b>-</b>6 to 8 dark, vertical bands on side.
                                           \n\n<b>-</b>Light yellow body with white underside.
                                           \n\n<b>-</b>Large mouth, extending to below the middle of the eye.</string>
    <string name="yellow_perch_size"><b>-</b>Length: 15-30 centimetres (6-12 inches)
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.35 kilograms (0.75 pounds)
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 1.1 kilograms (2.4 pounds)</string>
    <string name="yellow_perch_habitat">The Yellow Perch is a cool-water species and is most abundant in the open water of lakes with moderate vegetation, clear water and bottoms of muck, sand or gravel.
                                        \n\nYellow Perch spawn in lake shallows or rivers near aquatic plants or other cover. Yellow Perch do not make nests.</string>

    <!--Input data for Wallete-->
    <string name="walleye_overview">The Walleye is a perch like fish and a keen eyesight with the oldest reported age for the fish being 29.</string>
    <string name="walleye_appearance"><b>-</b>Large, elongated body.
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Back is olive-green to brown; side paler with yellow flecks.
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>White tip on lower tail fin.
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Large teeth.
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Spiny and soft dorsal fins are separated.</string>
    <string name="walleye_size"><b>-</b>Typical length: 35.5-58.4 centimetres (14-23 inches)
                                \n\n<b>-</b>Typical weight: 0.68-1.36 kilograms (1.5-3 pounds)
                                \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 10.1 kilograms (22.3 pounds)</string>
    <string name="walleye_habitat">Walleye are large predators adapted to low light and are found in large, shallow turbid lakes and the deeper waters of clear lakes.
                                   \n\nSpawning occurs in small groups that engage in chasing, circular swimming and fin erection. Spawning can happen in both river rapids and lake shoals.</string>

    <!--Input data for Muskellunge-->
    <string name="muskellunge_overview">The Muskellunge is a large freshwater fish that can reach speeds of up to 48 kilometres per hour and can live for as long as 30 years.</string>
    <string name="muskellunge_appearance"><b>-</b>Very large, elongated body.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Dark vertical bands on light background, at time spotted or clear.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Beige to white belly.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Partially scaled cheek and gill cover.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>12-18 pores on underside of lower jaw.</string>
    <string name="muskellunge_size"><b>-</b>Length: 71-137 centimetres (28-40 inches)
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 4-11 kilograms (8-23 pounds)
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 29.5 kilograms (65.0 pounds)</string>
    <string name="muskellunge_habitat">Muskellunge inhabit clear vegetated lakes, quiet pools, and the backwater of creeks and small to large rivers.</string>

    <!--Input data for Rock Bass-->
    <string name="rock_bass_overview">The Rock Bass is a freshwater fish native to east-central North America with its defining characteristic being a large red eye.</string>
    <string name="rock_bass_appearance"><b>-</b>Small and deep-bodied.
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Large, red eye.
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Adults have regular rows of spots along the side.
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Back and upper sides are brown to olive.
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Dorsal fin has 10 to 13 spines.</string>
    <string name="rock_bass_size"><b>-</b>Length: 15-20 centimetres (6-8 inches)
                                  \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.2 kilograms (0.4 pounds)
                                  \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 1.4 kilograms (3.0 pounds)</string>
    <string name="rock_bass_habitat">Rock Bass prefer clear, rocky and vegetated stream pools and lake margins. Rock can also commonly be seen swimming with other sunfish and bass.
                                     \n\nWhen spawning, males will build nests in shallow waters ranging from marshes to gravel sites.</string>

    <!--Input data for White Crappie-->
    <string name="white_crappie_overview">The White Crappie is a moderately large, fresh water fish that has deep, slightly longer body than a black crappie.</string>
    <string name="white_crappie_appearance"><b>-</b>Six dorsal fin spines.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>6 or 7 anal fin spines.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Side of the body has faint vertical bars.</string>
    <string name="white_crappie_size"><b>-</b>Length: 20-30 centimetres (8-12 inches)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.1 - 0.23 kilograms (0.25 - 0.5 pounds)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 1.26 kilograms (2.78 pounds)</string>
    <string name="white_crappie_habitat">The White Crappie resides in the mouths of small creeks or streams and in weedy, sheltered bays.
                                         \n\nWhile spawning occurs on a variety of bottom types, the White Crappie tend to spawn adjacent to aquatic plants or undercut banks.</string>

    <!--Input data for Common Carp-->
    <string name="common_carp_overview">The Common Carp is a fish that is widely distributed throughout North America despite being originally introduced in the 1880\'s by Europeans.</string>
    <string name="common_carp_appearance"><b>-</b>Large, deep-bodied fish.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Barbels (whiskers) beside mouth.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Back and sides vary from silver to olive-green, brassy or grey.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Yellowish belly.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Partially scaled cheek and gill cover.</string>
    <string name="common_carp_size"><b>-</b>Length: 30-75 centimetres (12-30 inches)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Width: 0.2-3.5 kilograms (0.5-7 pounds)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 17.4 kilograms (38.5 pounds)</string>
    <string name="common_carp_habitat">The Common Carp is able to adapt to a large variety of habitats including warm,shallow, weedy lakes and river to urban areas and habitats typically unsuitable for other fish.
                                       \n\nCarp typically in weedy,grassy, shallow areas of lakes and watercourses, usually about 2-3 feet deep. </string>

    <!--Input data for Rainbow Trout-->
    <string name="rainbow_trout_overview">The Rainbow Trout were previously only native to the west coast and the rocky mountains. In 1895, they were introduced into the Great Lakes and throughout Ontario.</string>
    <string name="rainbow_trout_appearance"><b>-</b>Silver body with many small dark spots.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Radiating rows of spots over tail.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Pink lateral strip often present.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>More prominent pink stripe on inland Rainbow Trout.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>White gums and mouth.
                                            \n\n<b>-</b>Long, stocky caudal peduncle.</string>
    <string name="rainbow_trout_size"><b>-</b>Length: 20-60 centimetres (8-24 inches)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.5 -6.8 kilograms (1-15 pounds)
                                      \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 18.5 kilograms (40.7 pounds)</string>
    <string name="rainbow_trout_habitat">Currently, the distribution of the Rainbow Trout is concentrated around the Great Lakes and St. Lawrence river. The habitat of the Rainbow Trout
                                         also includes cold streams, swift/turbulent water and a range of conditions in rivers, ponds and lakes.</string>

    <!--Input data for Brook Trout-->
    <string name="brook_trout_overview">The only native river trout in Ontario, fishing for the Brook Trout is an age old sport that goes back hundreds of years.</string>
    <string name="brook_trout_appearance"><b>-</b>Back is olive-green, brown or black.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Belly is silvery or white.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Square tail.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Mouth extends backwards well beyond the eye.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Light markings and posts on dark background, some red and blue.</string>
    <string name="brook_trout_size"><b>-</b>Length: 15-40 centimetres (6-16 inches)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.45 - 1.36 kilograms (1-3 pounds)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 6.6 kilograms (14.5 pounds)</string>
    <string name="brook_trout_habitat">Brook Trout can be found in much of southern Ontario farmland to the larger rivers, ponds and lakes of the North. Within these areas, the fish resides under cover of
                                       overhanging branches, logs or rocks, streams with quiet pools between runs of fast water or clear, cold lakes.</string>

    <!--Input data for Channel Catfish-->
    <string name="channel_catfish_overview">A popular recreational fish, the Channel Catfish is a slow growing fish with ages being reported of up to 40. </string>
    <string name="channel_catfish_appearance"><b>-</b>Large, elongated body with no scales.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>4 pairs of dark barbels around the mouth.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Pale blue, pale olive or grey back.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Tail is more forked than a bullhead\'s.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Grey to yellow to silver-white belly.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Lighter sides, often with black-spots.</string>
    <string name="channel_catfish_size"><b>-</b>Length: 36-53 centimetres (14-21 inches)
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.9-1.8 kilograms (2-4 pounds)
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 13.2 kilograms (38.5 pounds)</string>
    <string name="channel_catfish_habitat">Channel catfish prefer cooler deeper water with sand, gravel or rubble bottoms. They can often be found in areas of rivers with high current.
                                           \n\nSpawning for the Channel Catfish typically occurs in late spring or early summer. They spawn in secluded areas such as undercut banks, under logs or in spaces within rock piles.</string>

    <!--Input data for Smallmouth Bass-->
    <string name="smallmouth_bass_overview">The Smallmouth Bass is a popular recreational fish that only native to some areas of Ontario, but has since been spread throughout Northeastern and Northwestern Ontario.</string>
    <string name="smallmouth_bass_appearance"><b>-</b>Medium-sized, deep-bodied fish.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Green to olive back and side.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Yellow to white belly.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Upper jaw does not extend beyond eye.
                                              \n\n<b>-</b>Shallow notch between dorsal fins.</string>
    <string name="smallmouth_bass_size"><b>-</b>Length: 15-20 centimetres (10-20 inches)
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.5-1.6 kilograms (1-3.5 pounds)
                                        \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 4.5 kilograms (9.8 pounds)</string>
    <string name="smallmouth_bass_habitat">Smallmouth Bass favour rocky areas of lakes, especially points and will reside over boulder strewn mid-lake shoals. In summer, they may seek
                                           shade provided by an overhanging tree, dock or boats. Smallmouth Bass can also be found in similar habitat to trout but with a wider range of temperatures.
                                           \n\nSmallmouth Bass will create nests in up to 10 feet of water and is limited by the availability of gravel beds.</string>

    <!--Input data for Pumpkinseed-->
    <string name="pumpkinseed_overview">The Pumpkinseed is a deep bodied, compressed fish with its defining feature being a red spot on the tip of the gill plate.</string>
    <string name="pumpkinseed_appearance"><b>-</b>Small, very deep-bodied fish.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Wavy, blue-green stripes on sides of head.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Ear flap with orange or red spot.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Small mouth does not extend to below the middle of the eye.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>3 anal fin spines.
                                          \n\n<b>-</b>Unnotched dorsal fin with 10 to 11 spins.</string>
    <string name="pumpkinseed_size"><b>-</b>Length: 18-23 centimetres (7-9 inches)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.2 kilograms (0.4 pounds)
                                    \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 0.5 kilograms (1.0 pounds)</string>
    <string name="pumpkinseed_habitat">The preferred habitat of the Pumpkinseed is small lakes and ponds with clear water but can be found in weedy bays of larger lakes.
                                       \n\nFor spawning, males construct a nest in depths shallower than 12 inches, usually in areas with lots of submerged vegetation,</string>

    <!--Input data for Lake Trout-->
    <string name="lake_trout_overview">Lake trout are the largest of the freshwater char and have been reported to live up to 40 years.</string>
    <string name="lake_trout_appearance"><b>-</b>Green, grey, brown or almost black back.
                                         \n\n<b>-</b>White belly and light sides.
                                         \n\n<b>-</b>Light wormlike markings and spot on dark background.
                                         \n\n<b>-</b>Deeply forked tail.
                                         \n\n<b>-</b>White leading edge on lower fins, but no black lines.</string>
    <string name="lake_trout_size"><b>-</b>Length: 30-80 centimetres (12-31 inches)
                                   \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 1-5 kilograms (2-10 pounds)
                                   \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 28.6 kilograms (63.1 pounds)</string>
    <string name="lake_trout_habitat">Most Lake Trout inhabit deep lakes although they can exist in freshwater streams. Lake Trout rarely occur in brackish water.
                                      \n\nLake Trout prefer to spawn over large areas of lakes with boulder or rubble bottoms but are occasionally known to spawn in rivers. The eggs fall into cracks and
                                        crevices where they will remain for four to five months before hatching.</string>

    <!--Input data for Sauger-->
    <string name="sauger_overview">The Sauger is a freshwater perciform fish that is resembles its close relative the walleye.</string>
    <string name="sauger_appearance"><b>-</b>Large, elongated body.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Grey to brown back with 3-4 darker brown saddles.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Lacks the Walleye\'s white tip on lower tail fin.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Distinct blotches or bands on adults.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>White belly.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Spots on dorsal fin.
                                     \n\n<b>-</b>Separate spiny and soft dorsal fin.</string>
    <string name="sauger_size"><b>-</b>Length: 25-41 centimetres (10-16 inches)
                               \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.2-0.9 kilograms (0.5-2 pounds)
                               \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 2.0 kilograms (4.4 pounds)</string>
    <string name="sauger_habitat">Sauger enjoys similar habitats to its cousin, the walleye. Their habitats include: murky lakes and large rivers, soft mud bottoms to flooded timber, rubble or bedrock.</string>

    <!--Input data for Lake Whitefish-->
    <string name="lake_whitefish_overview">The Lake Whitefish is one the most abundant and important commercial freshwater species found in Canada.</string>
    <string name="lake_whitefish_appearance"><b>-</b>Greenish-brown back.
                                             \n\n<b>-</b>Silvery Sides.
                                             \n\n<b>-</b>Silvery-white belly.
                                             \n\n<b>-</b>Snout overhangs mouth.
                                             \n\n<b>-</b>Deeply forked tail.</string>
    <string name="lake_whitefish_size"><b>-</b>Length: 30-65 centimetres (12-26 inches)
                                       \n\n<b>-</b>Weight: 0.9-1.8 kilograms (2-4 pounds)
                                       \n\n<b>-</b>Ontario record: 6.7 kilograms (14.8 pounds)</string>
    <string name="lake_whitefish_habitat">Lake Whitefish prefer deep sections of deep lakes and shallow sections if Far North Lakes. During the heat of the summer, whitefish will seek deeper, cooler waters.
                                          \n\nSpawning typically occurs in November or December in depths no greater then 25 feet. Lake Whitefish will typically spawn on rocky bottoms or shoals.</string>
</resources>